(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E10 -= Dirt.Bike =- Subripped by zerox
信来了，电话帐单 还有你妈妈的信
Mail's here. Telephone bill, letter from your mother.
西蒙公司的杂志？
"Simones of Syosset, Sexy Sleepwear."
-这是干嘛？ -不知道
- I wonder how we got this. - I don't know.
上面写着寄\给杰森.西弗医生
Could it be because it's addressed to a Dr. Jason Seaver?
是吗？
Is it now?
自从我定购了流行歌曲杂志.
You know, I've been getting this darn junk mail ever since I sent away for...
这些垃圾邮件就源源不断
Slim Whitman's Greatest Hits.
“冬装”呢
"The winter catalog."
女人穿这个准冻死了
Jason, a woman could freeze in an outfit like this.
但是能让我暖和
It'd keep me warm.
真是的：“无缝，无带，无阻隔”
I can't believe this. "Seamless, strapless, see-through....
“蓝色，红色..”
"Blueberry, raspberry...
“混色”？
"trail mix"?
胡乱混合也很好玩的
Well, who says you can't eat well and have a little fun, too?
我同意!
Not me!
-妈妈，你在看什么？ -饮食杂志.
- What you reading, Mom? - Just this diet magazine...
刚寄\来的，都是些废话
we got in the mail. It's garbage.
爸爸，妈妈，别吓坏了!
Mom, Dad, hold on to your hats!
我在车房发现一只斑雀
We have got a speckled chickadee out by the garage.
怎样？
So?
怎样？女人啊!
"So? " Good God, woman!
斑雀几乎只能在.
Don't you realize that the speckled chickadee is almost...
阿迪达克山谷下游才能看到
exclusively indigenous to the lower Adirondack Valley?
-这可是自然奇观 -我们家也有个自然奇观
- We have got a freak of nature out there. - We've got a freak of nature in here, too.
麦克，我还不知道你这么热爱大自然
Gee, Mike, I didn't realize you we're such a woodsy kind of guy.
我？当然了
Me? Heck, yeah.
有时候我感到在野外比房间里更舒适
I mean, sometimes I feel more at home outdoors than I do in my own bedroom.
因为野外比你的房间干净
That's because outdoors is cleaner.
爸爸，我是说真的
No, I'm serious, Dad.
大自然能够舒缓都市生活的压力
Natures always been a great release for me from the pressures of suburban life.
-所以你就想.. -周末去野营.
- And that's why what you want-- - Is to go camping with Jimmy and Boner...
吉米，邦纳，还有他哥哥米奇
and Boners older brother, Mitch.
米奇是全校最成熟的一个
He's the most mature guy in the whole high school.
都21了，也该熟了吧？
He ought to be. He's 21.
你和朋友打算怎样度周末？
So, Mike, what do you and your friends plan to do all weekend?
自由地呼吸
Breathe free, Mom.
接着感谢什么？
And once you get the hang of that, then what happens?
接着是普通的玩意
Then, the usual.
登山，钓鱼..车.
A little fishing, hiking, dirt biking...
-观鸟这些事情 -等等
- bird watching. Stuff like that. - Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
观鸟前面是什么？
What was that right before bird watching?
车.
Dirt biking.
我说摩托飞车
Dirt biking. I said dirt biking, okay?
杰森，我们..厅谈谈
Jason, may I have a word with you in the living room?
什么？
What?
她说“我们..厅谈谈”
She said, "May I have a word with you in the living room? "
你们这是怎么了？
What's wrong with you people?
现在到了..厅
Well, here we are in the living room...
谈谈麦克的..车
to discuss Mike dirt biking.
杰森，我们应该联合起来对付孩子
Come on, Jason. I think it's important that we present a unified front to the kids.
-能听到他们说话就好了 -我知道她们说什么
- I wish I knew what they we're saying. - I know what they're saying.
“我们应该联合起来对付孩子”
"We've got to present a unified front to the kids."
爸爸回答.. “算了，麦姬，虽然麦克老闯祸”
And Dad is saying, "Come on, Maggie. I know Mikes screwed up before...
“但总不能让他呆在温室里”
"but we can't raise the kid in a bubble."
接着妈妈说.. “温室没什么不好”
And Mom is saying, "I don't see why not.
“以前还不是这样”
"It's not like it's never been done before."
爸爸会说“麦姬，你反应过度了”
And Dad is saying, "Maggie, you're overreacting."
我没有反应过度
I am not overreacting.
我不希望他把命也丢了
I just don't want to see him get himself killed up there.
亲爱的，在家也能送命
Honey, he could get killed right here.
掉下楼梯会摔死，浸浴会淹死
He could fall down the stairs, he could drown in the tub.
甚至吃牛肉会哽死
He could choke on my pastrami surprise.
我决定了，明天要建一座温室
Well, that does it. Tomorrow, we're gonna get that kid a bubble.
别耍了，不让我去是因为野营好玩
Come on, who's kidding who? They're not gonna let me go camping because it's fun.
-麦克？ -知道了.
- Mike? - I know, I know...
你们的生活没有乐趣 所以我也不能有
you guys don't have any fun, so you don't want me to have any fun.
麦克，他们是想没有你
Mike, they didn't want to have you.
麦克，我们决定让你去
Mike, we decided to let you go camping.
我可以去？好啊!
I can? All right!
但不能玩摩托飞车
But you can't go dirt biking.
不能玩摩托？爸爸，这是什么意思？
I can't go dirt biking? Dad, what does she mean, I can't go dirt biking?
我的理解是“不能玩摩托”的意思
Well, my interpretation would be you can't go dirt biking.
你们就是不让我有乐趣
I knew you guys didn't want me to have any fun.
这不是乐趣问题，是性命问题
Mike, it's not a question of fun. It's a question of death.
但我在家里也会死
But, Mom, I could get killed right here at home.
坦白说，我和你妈商量过后.. 决定宁愿、让你死在家里
Well, frankly, your mother and I discussed that, and we'd prefer it that way.
真叫人不敢相信
All right. I don't believe you guys.
麦克，请考虑一下这个.
Hey, Mike, there's something you ought to consider here.
我们完全有理由不让你去
We don't have to let you go at all!
突然梦变了
And all of a sudden, the dream changes.
我在浴室刷牙，突然牙齿不见了
I'm in the bathroom brushing my teeth. And then, they're not my teeth anymore.
脸也变了，坏陋不堪
And it's not my face. It gets all ugly and weird.
我似乎变成了怪物 或者变成了麦克!
It's either The Elephant Man or Mike!
-接着呢？ -后面记不清了
- And then? - This part gets a little fuzzy.
本，钱已经付了
Ben, I paid you at the beginning of this dream.
但这个梦特别长
But this ones extra long.
我只是个要写论文的穷学生
Look, I'm a poor student working on a paper.
从今以后，1个梦5毛钱，当面付清
Okay, but from now on, it's 50 cents per dream, up front...
不论长短
no matter what the length.
现在想起来了
It's clear now.
是麦克!我变成了麦克
It is Mike. I've turned into Mike!
我在打自己
I'm beating myself up.
我在浪费青春 而且竟然因为愚蠢而浑然不知
My life is wasted, but I'm too stupid to know it!
-太棒了 -接着我醒了
- Fascinating. - And then I wake up.
还做别的梦了吗？
So, did you have any other dreams last night?
没有，只做了1个
No, that was the only one.
本，我需要大量材料来分析
But, Ben, I need more material to analyze.
凯罗，现在是大白天
Carol, it's the middle of the day.
怎么能睡着，我需要点东西来.
I can't just fall asleep. I need something to relax me...
让我放松，让我进入状态
to get me in the mood.
现在我困了
Suddenly, I'm getting drowsy.
-你好 -杰森，让你看个东西
- Hello. - Jason, I want you to see something.
睡衣杂志
The Simones catalog.
你不是扔了吗？
I thought you threw that away.
是扔了，但它跑回来了
Oh, I did. But somehow, it found it's way back home.
也许某位好心人在垃圾堆里看到.
Well, maybe some good Samaritan passing by saw it fall out of the garbage...
照着地址寄\回来了
noticed the address, and returned it.
-还补好了 -他非常细心
- And taped it back together? - A very good Samaritan.
还塞进我的内衣柜子
And slipped it into my lingerie drawer?
他真是个天大的好人
Possibly a great Samaritan.
杰森.
Jason...
我感到你要我穿这种睡衣
something tells me that you'd like to see me in one of those outfits.
-没有 -一件也不要？
- No. - Not even a little bit?
-我不是那样的人 -当然了
- I'm not that kind of guy. - Of course not, Jason.
假设你一定要做那种人，例如.
But if you had to be that kind of guy, I mean, et's just say...
我用枪指着你，你会选哪款？
there was a gun at your head, which one would you pick?
麦姬，行了.
Maggie, I didn't even--
17页2693号
Page 17, item 2693...
-带哨子那款 -哨子
- with the whistle. - Oh, the whistle.
突然想起来的
Just off the top of my head.
“野性的呼唤”？
"Call Of The Wild"?
粉红色的
In pink.
本做了个荒谬的梦
Boy, Ben had the weirdest dream.
看来他内心深处对麦克很焦虑
I think he's got some deep-rooted anxieties toward Mike.
有谁不是呢？
Who doesn't?
-但愿、我不是 -麦姬
- I wish I didn't. - Maggie.
他到野外去了，跟邦纳在一起
Jason, he's out there in the wilderness, with Boner.
-难道咱们错了？ -错在.
- Did we make a mistake? - Maybe.
15年前生下了他 我们说过不要担心这事的
Fifteen years ago. But we agreed not to worry about it this weekend.
希望他平安无事
I know. I just hope he's okay.
他沉吟道.. “安妮，我需要你，因为我是男人”
""l want you, Jo Anne. I need you because I'm a man, he snorted.
“这么快，我终于能实现..”
"And so at last, finally, I mean now...
-“我的美梦了” -美梦是什么？
- ""l get to realize my dream."" - Which is?
“下期继续刊登”
"To be continued in next months issue."
这杂志连插图也没有
Oh, great! This thing doesn't even have a centerfold.
邦纳，这算什么破玩意
Way to go, Boner.
西弗，到你了
You're up, Seaver.
米奇，我说过了，这玩意.
Look, Mitch, I told you, I dirt biked my brains out last summer...
去年夏天我就玩够了
and I'm kind of burned out on the experience.
等等，上星期你还说.
Wait a minute, Seaver. Didn't you tell me last week...
从没玩过这个
that you'd never tried one of these?
对，因为这是大岛705
Yeah, one of these. I mean, this the Oshima 705.
我玩过702，703，704，几乎其他全部
Now, I've tried the 702, 703, 704, and almost everything else.
大岛车没有704这款
Oshima don't make a 704, Seaver.
对，因为我测试原型后.
Yeah, because when I tested the prototype...
告诉他们704很垃圾
I told them it was a piece of garbage.
小麦克，你害怕705？
You're not afraid of the 705, are you, Mikey?
哥们，我不能骑这个
Hey, look, guys, I'm just not supposed to.
谁说的？你妈妈？
Who says? Your mommy?
不是我妈妈
No, not my mommy.
你们不要老是开玩笑了
"My mommy." The jokes don't stop coming with you guys, do they?
事实是.
Well, you see, the fact is that...
有几位名医对我说，再骨折的话.
several prominent doctors have advised that breaking any more bones could...
可能会毁掉我的职业生涯
kind of ruin my chances of turning pro.
世界上竟有职业脓包
I didn't know they had professional wusses.
-他不是个脓包 -对，他不是
- Hey, I'm not a wuss, okay? - No, no, no, he's not a wuss.
他只是像个脓包
He just does a good imitation of one.
够了!
Knock it off!
麦克要生气了
Mikey's mad.
车给我，给我
Give me the bike. Just give me the bike.
我不会表演杂技
I'm not doing any stunts.
瞧他开车
Look at him go.
原来摩托车能这样开
Wow! I didn't realize those things could go through a bush like that.
现在用手臂勾住把手
Now he's got his elbows wrapped around the handlebars.
勾住排气管
Look, he's hanging from the tail pipe!
还说不表演杂技
And he said he wasn't gonna do any stunts.
天哪!
Holy cow!
找不着他
I couldn't find him anywhere.
他堕崖了？
You don't think he went over the cliff, do you?
我们有更多排骨吃了
Well, if he did, that means more ribs for us.
哥们，怎样？
Hey, guys. How's it going?
天哪，还以为你死了
Gee, Seaver. We thought you bought it up there.
你是说刚才的跳车表演？
You mean my trick dismount?
你刚才难道是故意的？
You mean, you expect us to believe that you did that on purpose?
当然了，你们是我朋友却那么笨
Yeah. Of course, I do. Look, you"re my friends. You're not all that bright.
瞧他裤子背后
Look at the back of his pants.
裤子背后怎么了？
What's wrong with the back of my pants?
没有了
They're not there.
还是让他看医生吧
We better go home and get him to a doctor.
我没事，真的 我得歇一歇
No, no, man. Look, I'm fine, really. I just need to sit down for a minute.
请问你叫什么名字？
May I have your name again, sir?
巴富米罗.麦曼纳斯
McManus. Bartholomew McManus.
-巴富米罗先生 -叫我巴斯就好了
- Well, Bartholomew-- - Just call me Barth.
好的，巴斯先生 医生马上就来
Okay, Barth. The doctor will see you in a moment.
-请坐 -好的
- Why don't you just have a seat? - Okay.
不了，我坐一整天了
No, no, I sit all day.
我需要克兰登的X光照片.
I'll need Mrs. Cramden's x-rays....
-麦克!麦克.西弗 -麦克斯基医生？
- Michael! Michael Seaver. - Dr. McCloskey!
周末也上班？
Look, I didn't think you worked on weekends.
-不是有代班医生吗？ -埃米特医生？
- Don't you have that substitute doctor? - Oh, you mean Dr. Emmett?
你本周放假
No, he's on vacation this week.
你这么忙，我改天再来吧
You must be very busy. Look, I'll come back some other time.
胡说，上来
Nonsense, nonsense. Jump up here.
什么事了？
Now what seems to be the trouble?
原来如此，让我瞧瞧
I guess that says it all. Well have a look.
-破皮而已 -麦克，大事不妙
- It's just a little scratch, Doc. - That looks bad, Mike.
分成两半了
It's broken in half.
痛吗？
That hurt?
不痛，刚才谁叫喊了？
No, no, not really. Was that you?
怎么弄成这样了？
How did this happen, Mike?
事实上，天生就是这样的
To tell you the truth, Doc, it's kind of always been like this.
-我是装的 -麦克!
- It's just acting up. - Mike?
好吧，好吧 我在派对里坐在热煎饼上了
Okay, okay, I was at a party and I sat on a hot pizza.
看上去是擦破皮
Well, there seem to be some abrasions.
那是烫伤
Those are cheese burns.
那上面的肉汁呢？
And what about the gravel?
没有叫肉汁煎饼
We didn't order that.
我穿着内衣飞过纽约上空
So I'm flying over New York in my underwear...
人们突然叫嚷.. “那个人内衣穿反了!”
and then, all of a sudden, people start yelling, "Hey, look! It's on inside out! "
在你作为被遗忘的肯尼迪家族成员前.
Now, is this before or after the one where you we're...
还是之后？
Ben, the forgotten Kennedy.
之前，紧接着.
It was before that, and after the one...
我变成一只人肉热狗后
where I turned into the human hot dog.
本，我的报告要打分的
Ben, you know I'm getting graded on this paper.
你没有瞎编骗我吧？
You're not just making this stuff up, are you?
没有，这些梦都是真的
No, Carol. These are real dreams.
敢发誓？
You swear?
上帝可以作证，没有一个梦是编的
Cross my heart. I'd never make up a dream.
这些材料足以.
Great. Well, this should be enough for a penetrating...
深入分析本的心理世界了
psychological profile of the real Ben Seaver.
深入且利润丰厚
Penetrating and profitable.
杰森，你疯了？
Jason, you are crazy.
因为我狂野？
Why, cause I was born to be wild?
不，因为你把车开到我客厅里了
No, because you have a dirt bike in my living room.
此刻，一个闷闷不乐的少年在山上.
Well, we also have a very unhappy boy up at Bear Mountain right now.
我为什么不租一辆车教教他呢
So I thought why not go out, rent a bike, and teach him to ride myself.
多美好，多可怕
What a sweet and incredibly terrifying idea.
麦姬，我自有分寸
Maggie, I know what I'm doing.
话说回来，我是骑哈利跑车长大的
I used to ride a Harley, for crying out loud.
我知道，我还到医院探望你了
I know, sweetheart. I visited you in the hospital.
当时平地冒出一头牛!
Hey, that cow came out of nowhere.
-我要宰了你 -我也宰了你
- I'm gonna kill you. - I'm gonna kill you back.
-你不能，因为你死了 -我慢慢死就行了
- You can"t. You'll be dead. - Not if I go slowly.
等等，杀人的事交给我吧
Hold on. I'll do the killing around here.
本搞砸了我的论文
Ben ruined my paper.
？
Not the portrait of the sleeping 9-year-old?
他说卖给我的梦都是真的
He said all the dreams he sold me we're real, and now I catch him...
但我在院子里看见他跟拉夫买恶梦
on the front lawn buying a nightmare from Ralph Finsterwald!
我说过梦是真的，没说梦是我的
Hey, I said they we're real dreams. I didn't say they we're mine.
-本! -向朋友买梦不行吗？
- Ben! - So I bought a few off some friends.
-我赚不了多少 -本!
- I barely broke even. - Ben.
好吧，好吧，我有两倍的利润 这算是罪大恶极了吗？
Okay, okay, so I made a 200% profit. Is that such a crime?
我的结论都没意义了，论文搞砸了
But you ruined my paper. Now all my conclusions are meaningless.
凯罗，也许你可以借题发挥
I don't know, Carol. I think there might still be a paper in this somewhere.
改成.
Say, the emergence of the criminal mind...
或是，例如.
or the effects of swift and severe punishment, such as...
整个周末帮姐姐干活
doing your sisters chores for a whole weekend?
什么？
What?
我看多于1周时间的数据才准确
I think it will take a lot more than a weekend to get reliable data.
至少1周
I need at least a week.
很好，本，你认为呢？
Sounds like a good idea to me. What do you say, Ben?
我认为不好
I hate it.
好吧，那就1个月
Okay, well make it a month.
1周很公道
A week sounds fair.
本，本.
Ben, Ben....
千万别出卖自己的梦
Never sell your dreams.
除非价钱很好
Not at these prices.
-麦克？ -吗
- Mike? - Mom!
你更苗条了!
Have you lost weight!
你在这干什么？
What are you doing here?
在这干什么？
Here? Here, Mom?
那我问你：我们在这里干什么？
Let me ask you this: What are any of us doing here?
这是个永恒的问题 某已故哲学家说过.
I mean, it's a timeless question. I think a dead philosopher once said--
-麦克，你在这干什么？ -爸爸!
- Mike, what are you doing here? - Dad!
你更苗条了!
Have you lost weight?
怎么提早一天回来了？
Mike, how come you're home a day early?
事实上.
Well, to tell you the truth, Mom...
我和邦纳吵架了
I kind of got in a little argument with Boner.
真遗憾，但回家就好
I'm sorry to hear that, but I'm glad you're home, Mike...
我有惊喜给你
cause I have a surprise for you.
来看看
Come on, take a look.
麦克，怎么这样走路
Mike, how come you're walking like that?
保持神秘感嘛
I'm just trying to keep the suspense alive, Mom.
就在这里!不是重型机车是什么？
There she is, Mike! Is that a mean machine, or what?
这是大岛705型 看过这种宝贝没有？
It is the Oshima 705. You ever see one of these babies?
看过一次，相反方向驶过
Yeah, once. it was going the other way.
这是你爸周末租的 他会教你怎么骑
Your father rented it for the weekend so he could teach you how to ride.
好爸爸，好朋友，好家伙
Oh, gee! What a dad. What a pal. What a guy.
我要睡觉了
Well, I'm off to bed now.
麦克
Mike, bike.
-上来试试 -试什么？在哪？
- Come on, plant that duff up here. - Which duff? Where?
麦克!来!上车!
Come on, Mike! et's go! Hop on!
真舒服
Ah, comfortable.
快坐下，又不会咬你
Come on, sit down. It's not going to bite you.
避震很好
It's got great suspension, too.
看来他很喜欢
Maggie, I think he likes it.
我感到迎面吹来的风了
I can feel the wind in our hair already.
-杰森，过来聊两句 -爸爸，快聊
- Jason, might I have a word with you? - Yeah, Dad, have words.
慢慢聊
Have lots of words.
还是聊天比较好
Nothing that says it quite like words.
杰森，麦克斯基医生打来了
Jason, that was Dr. McCloskey on the phone.
-麦克今天找他了 -找他干嘛？
- Seems Mike stopped by there today. - Yeah? What for?
臀部破皮淤青
Turns out he has some pretty bad bruises and abrasions on his gluteal region.
麦克怎么不告诉我们？
Why didn't he tell us?
这伤有可能是.
Now, could these be the kind of bruises that you get from...
摩托飞车造成的？
say, falling off a dirt bike?
我也这样问麦克斯基医生
I just happened to ask Dr. McCloskey the same question.
他怎么说？
And he said?
“不然就是刮毛严重失误”
It's either that, or a freak shaving accident.
麦克!
Oh, Mike!
爸爸？
Yeah, Dad?
-准备好去骑车没？ -现在？
- Ready to go biking? - Now, Dad?
对，来吧，咱们骑这玩意.
Yeah. Come on. We're gonna take this little puppy over...
逛逛纽约最崎岖的地方
some of the roughest terrain on Long Island.
你爸找了一天的坑洼地
You know, your father was out all day scouting for potholes.
-坑洼地？ -是的
- Potholes? - Yeah.
是男人的话就不用垫子
And if you we're real men, you'd do it without shock absorbers.
拿下来怎么样？
et's take them off, Mike. What do you say?
不，不要了，骑摩托车是很危险的
No, Dad, I don't think we should do this. I mean, dirt bikes are death machines.
人们常常摔伤
People fall off and get hurt.
不可能，只有傻瓜才会摔伤
No way. No. Only a bone-brain would fall off.
屁股坐上来，咱们走
Come on. Let's get your rear in gear. Let's go, Mike.
来吗，麦克!
Come on, Mike!
别逼我了
Look, please don't make me.
为什么？
But why not?
因为我是个傻瓜
Because I'm a bone-brain, all right?
我骑这个时摔下来了
I mean, I fell off one of these things at Bear Mountain.
我答应过不骑，但出尔反尔 结果受伤了
I promised I wouldn't ride it, but I did, and I got hurt.
我没有理会你的警告 你说对了，你们总是对的
You warned me, I didn't listen to you. You we're right. You're always right.
我个人很讨厌这一点
And personally, I find that annoying.
你们是怎么了？
What is it with you people?
杰森，我们是怎么了？
I don't know, Jason. What is it with us people?
因为我们年长 这个我们也无法控制
We can't help it. We're older.
我们更有智慧
We're wiser.
这点也很讨厌
I find that annoying, too.
先听我说完
Then wait till you hear this.
你得留在房间里一周
I think we agree that you should spend the next week in your room.
我可以趴着吗？
Can I spend it lying on my face?
可以
All right.
谢谢
Thanks.
麦克.
And, Mike...
我们生气不是因为你骑摩托车.
what really upsets us is not just that you went and rode the dirt bike...
而是你想要骗我们
but that you tried to deceive us.
受伤了就要告诉我们
I mean, if you get hurt, we need to know.
若是告诉你们就不用惩罚
Does that mean that if I had told you guys I wouldn't be punished?
不
No.
只是确认一下
Just checking.
租两天真浪费
Well, what a pity to waste this. It's rented for the whole weekend.
这个嘛.
Well, I don't know....
真是性感
Hot. Very hot.
这两天就坐在车上吧
Can you sit like that for the entire rental period?
这样吧，我们骑车出去转一圈
Well, I've got a better idea. Why don't we just take a little spin upstairs?
我今天要购物
I did a little shopping at Simones of Syosset today. I picked up...
买那款睡衣
Call of the Wild.
粉红色那款？
In pink?
巧克力色那款
In chocolate.
麦克，走了
Come on, Mike. et's go.
我不去
I'm not going.
拜托，要赶不上电影了
Oh, come on, Mike, well miss the movie.
人们会看到我的
But, Mom, people will see me.
不会的，可以在车上看
No, they won"t. It's a drive-in.
好吧
Okay.
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.03.12